<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rows>

<row id="1">
	<Name>Hyper-Expansion</Name>
	<Description>You must expand to survive. You are given a small and cheap colony hull and an engine which travels at Warp 6 using no fuel. Your race will grow at twice the growth rate you select in step four; however, the maximum population for a given planet is cut in half. The completely flexible Meta Morph hull will be available only to your race.</Description>

	<Cost>-10</Cost>

	<Max_Pop>50</Max_Pop>
	<Grow_bonus>200</Grow_bonus>

	<Ship_hull>Scout</Ship_hull>
	<Ship_type>Cargo</Ship_type>
	<Ship_name>Armed Scout</Ship_name>
	<Ship_qty>1</Ship_qty>
	
	<Ship_hull>Mini-Colony Ship</Ship_hull>
	<Ship_type>Colony Ship</Ship_type>
	<Ship_name>Colony Ship</Ship_name>
	<Ship_qty>3</Ship_qty>

</row>

<row id="2">
<Name>Super Stealth</Name>
	<Description>You can sneak through enemy territory and execute stunning surprise attacks. You are given top-drawer cloaks and all your ships have 75% cloaking built-in. Cargo does not decrease your cloaking abilities. The Stealth Bomber and Rogue are at your disposal, as are a scanner, shield and armor with stealthy properties. Two scanners which allow you to steal minerals from enemy fleets and planets are so available. You may safety travel through mine fields at one warp faster than the limits.</Description>

	<Cost>-28</Cost>

	<Ele>5</Ele>

	<Ship1_tp>Scout</Ship1_tp>
	<Ship1_no>1</Ship1_no>
	<Ship2_tp>Colony</Ship2_tp>
	<Ship2_no>1</Ship2_no>

	<Cloak_Starbase_extra>300</Cloak_Starbase_extra>
	<Cloak_Ship_extra>300</Cloak_Ship_extra>
	
	<Mine_Speed>1</Mine_Speed>
	<Spy_Reserach>50</Spy_Reserach>
	
</row>

<row id="3">
<Name>War Monger</Name>
	<Description>You rule the battle field. Your colonists attack better, your ships are faster in battle, and you build weapons 25% cheaper than other races. You start the game with a knowledge of Tech 6 weapons and Tech 1 in energy and propulsion. Unfortunately, your race doesn't understand the necessity of building any but the most basic planetary  defences and no mine fields.</Description>

	<Cost>-12</Cost>

	<Wep>5</Wep>
	<Ene>1</Ene>
	<Prp>1</Prp>

	<Speed_Battle_extra>50</Speed_Battle_extra>
	<Colony_Attack_bonus>125</Colony_Attack_bonus>
	<Beam_Cost_bonus>75</Beam_Cost_bonus>
	<Torpedo_Cost_bonus>75</Torpedo_Cost_bonus>
	
	<Know_design_by_scan>1</Know_design_by_scan>

	<Ship1_tp>Armed</Ship1_tp>
	<Ship1_no>1</Ship1_no>
	<Ship2_tp>Colony</Ship2_tp>
	<Ship2_no>1</Ship2_no>
	
</row>

<row id="4">
	<Name>Claim Adjuster</Name>
	<Description>You are an expert at fiddling with planetary environments. You start the game with Tech 6 in Biotechnology and a ship capable of terraforming planet from orbit. You can arm your ships with bombs that unterraform enemy worlds. Terraforming Costs you nothing and planets you leave revert to their original environments. Planets you own have up to a 10% chance of permanently improving an environment variable by 1% per year.</Description>

	<Cost>0</Cost>

	<Wep>1</Wep>
	<Ene>1</Ene>
	<Prp>1</Prp>
	<Bio>6</Bio>

	<Terraform_Free>1</Terraform_Free>
	
</row>

<row id="5">
	<Name>Inner-Strength</Name>
	<Description>You are strong and hard to defeat. Your colonists repel attack better, your ships heal faster, you have special battle devices that protect your ships and can lay Speed Trap mine fields. You have a device that acts as both a shield and armor. Your peace-loving people refuse to build Smart Bombs. Planetary defences Cost you 40% less, thought weapons Cost you 25% more. Your colonists are able to reproduce while being transported by your fleets.</Description>

	<Cost>36</Cost>

	<Growth_pop_space_bonus>50</Growth_pop_space_bonus>

	<Colony_Defence_bonus>125</Colony_Defence_bonus>
	<Defence_Cost_bonus>60</Defence_Cost_bonus>

	<Ship1_tp>Scout</Ship1_tp>
	<Ship1_no>1</Ship1_no>
	<Ship2_tp>Colony</Ship2_tp>
	<Ship2_no>1</Ship2_no>
	
</row>

<row id="6">
	<Name>Space Demolition</Name>
	<Description>You are an expert in laying mine fields. You have a vast array of mine types at your disposal and two unique hull design which are made for mine dispersal. Your mine fields act as scanners and have the ability to remote detonate your own Standard mine fields. You may safely travel two warp speeds faster than the stated limits through enemy mine fields. You start the game with 2 mine laying ships and Tech 2 in Propulsion and Biotech.</Description>

	<Cost>53</Cost>

	<Prp>2</Prp>
	<Bio>2</Bio>

	<Mine_Speed_extra>2</Mine_Speed_extra>

	<Mine_Scan>1</Mine_Scan>
	<Mine_Explode>1</Mine_Explode>
	
	<Know_Design_Minehit>1</Know_Design_Minehit>
	
	<Mine_Planet>1</Mine_Planet>
	<Lay_Mine_Travel>1</Lay_Mine_Travel>

	<Ship1_tp>Scout</Ship1_tp>
	<Ship1_no>1</Ship1_no>
	<Ship2_tp>Colony</Ship2_tp>
	<Ship2_no>1</Ship2_no>
	<Ship3_tp>Mine</Ship3_tp>
	<Ship3_no>1</Ship3_no>
	<Ship4_tp>Trap</Ship4_tp>
	<Ship4_no>1</Ship4_no>
	
</row>

<row id="7">
	<Name>Packet Physics</Name>
	<Description>Your race excels at accelerating mineral packets to distant planets. You start with a Warp 5 accelerator at your home starbase and Tech 4 Energy. You will eventually be able to fling packets at the mind numbing speed of Warp 13. You can fling smaller packets and all of your packetshave penetrating scanners embedded in them. You will start the game owning a second planet  some distance away if the universe size isn't tiny. Packets you fling that aren't fully caught have a chance of terraforming the planet.</Description>

	<Cost>-37</Cost>
	
	<Ene>4</Ene>

	<Planets_Start>2</Planets_Start>
	<Packet_Scan>1</Packet_Scan>
	
	<Know_Packets_Loc>1</Know_Packets_Loc>
	<Know_Base_Packet>1</Know_Base_Packet>
	
	<Packet_Dmg>133</Packet_Dmg>
	<Packet_Hit_Pla>50</Packet_Hit_Pla>
	<Packet_Hit_Val>1</Packet_Hit_Val>
	<Packet_Unhit_Mass>100</Packet_Unhit_Mass>
	<Packet_Unhit_Pla>1</Packet_Unhit_Pla>
	<PPacket_Unhit_Val>1</PPacket_Unhit_Val>

	<Packet_W1>5</Packet_W1>
	<Packet_W2>10</Packet_W2>
	<Packet_W3>25</Packet_W3>
	<Packet_Cost_R>70</Packet_Cost_R>
	<Packet_Cost_M>50</Packet_Cost_M>

	<Ship1_tp>Shielded</Ship1_tp>
	<Ship1_no>2</Ship1_no>
	<Ship2_tp>Colony</Ship2_tp>
	<Ship2_no>1</Ship2_no>

</row>

<row id="8">
	<Name>Interstellar Traveller</Name>
	<Description>Your race excels in building stargates. You start with Tech 5 in Propulsion and Construction. You start the game with a second planet if the universe size isn't tiny. Both planets have stargates. Eventually you may build stargates which have unlimited capabilities. Stargates Cost you 25% less to build. Your race can automatically scan any enemy planet which a stargate which is in range of one of your stargates. Exceeding the safety limits of stargates is less likely to kill your ships.</Description>

	<Cost>-57</Cost>
	
	<Con>5</Con>
	<Prp>5</Prp>

	<Planets_Start>2</Planets_Start>

	<Packet_W0>10</Packet_W0>
	<Packet_W1>20</Packet_W1>
	<Packet_W2>50</Packet_W2>
	<Packet_W3>75</Packet_W3>

	<Packet_Catch>50</Packet_Catch>

	<Gatejump_Cargo>1</Gatejump_Cargo>
	<Gatejump_Colony>1</Gatejump_Colony>
	<Gatejump_Overload>1</Gatejump_Overload>

	<Know_Planets_Gate>1</Know_Planets_Gate>
	
	<Stargates_Cost>75</Stargates_Cost>

	<Ship1_tp>Scout</Ship1_tp>
	<Ship1_no>1</Ship1_no>
	<Ship2_tp>Colony</Ship2_tp>
	<Ship2_no>1</Ship2_no>
	<Ship3_tp>Destroyer</Ship3_tp>
	<Ship3_no>1</Ship3_no>
	<Ship4_tp>Prvateer</Ship4_tp>
	<Ship4_no>1</Ship4_no>
		
</row>

<row id="9">
	<Name>Alternate Reality</Name>
	<Description>You race developed in an alternate plane. Your people cannot survive on lanets and live in orbit on your starbase, which are 20% cheaper to build. You cannot build planetary installations, but your people have an intrinsic ability to mine and scan for enemy fleets. You can remote mine your own worlds. If a starbase is destroyed, all your colonists orbiting that world are killed. Your population maximums are determined by the type of starbase you have. You will eventually be able to build Death Star.</Description>

	<Cost>-27</Cost>
	
	<Kill_Colony_Space>3</Kill_Colony_Space>

	<Alterante_Reality>1</Alterante_Reality>

	<Starbase_Cost_bonus>80</Starbase_Cost_bonus>

</row>

<row id="10">
	<Name>Jack of All Trades</Name>
	<Description>Your race does not specialize in a single area. You start the game with Tech 3 in all areas and an assortment of ships. Your scout, Destroyer, and Frigate hulls have a built-in penetrating scanner which grows more powerful as your Electronics tech increases. Your inimum pplanetary population is 20% greater than other races.</Description>
	
	<Cost>25</Cost>
	
	<Wep>3</Wep>
	<Con>3</Con>
	<Ene>3</Ene>
	<Ele>3</Ele>
	<Prp>3</Prp>
	<Bio>3</Bio>
	
	<Max_Pop>120</Max_Pop>

	<Tech3_extra>1</Tech3_extra>

	<Penscan_1>1</Penscan_1>
	<Penscan_2>2</Penscan_2>
	<Penscan_3>3</Penscan_3>

	<Ship1_tp>Scout</Ship1_tp>
	<Ship1_no>2</Ship1_no>
	<Ship2_tp>Colony</Ship2_tp>
	<Ship2_no>1</Ship2_no>
	<Ship3_tp>Medium</Ship3_tp>
	<Ship3_no>1</Ship3_no>
	<Ship4_tp>Destroyer</Ship4_tp>
	<Ship4_no>1</Ship4_no>
	<Ship5_tp>Mini-digger</Ship5_tp>
	<Ship5_no>1</Ship5_no>
	
</row>
</rows>
